Register of the Hugh Gibson papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1902-1954 (Boxes 10-67)
  - Walden, (Daily Telegraph, London), 1936
  - Wales, Henry, undated
  - Walewska, Countess, 1920
  - Walker, Harold, 1935
  - Walker, L. C. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Hoover, Herbert, Correspondence], 1951-1954
  - Wall, Frank, undated
  - Wachtel, C. H., 1923 (Box 64)
  - Wallace, DeWitt, 1952-1953
  - Wallace, Hugh Campbell, 1922
  - Waller, George Platt, 1931-1953
  - Walling, William English, 1921
  - Walouiew [See: Valuyeff]
  - Walter, Francis, 1952
  - Walvjewski, 1924
  - Wambaugh, Sarah, 1927
  - Wands, Ernest H., 1931
  - Warburg, Felix A., (?), 1920
  - Warburton, Maj., 1918
  - Ward, Cabot, Col., 1918-1927
  - Ward, Robert E., 1953
  - Warner, Charles D., undated
  - Warner, Ernest, 1930
  - Warren, Avra M., 1936
  - Warren, George, 1952
  - Warren, Lee, 1932
  - Warren, R. L. (Mrs. Benjamin), undated
  - Warren, Whitney, 1928
  - Washburn, Albert, 1925
  - Washburn, G. E., Capt., 1925
  - Watkins, S. C. G., 1921
  - Watson, Edwin M. [See also: Houghton Mifflin Company], 1927-1942
  - Watson, J. B. S., 1930
  - Webb, C. A., 1931
  - Weddell, Alexander W. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Chaco War, Correspondence, Diplomatic], 1934-1936
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1954
  - Weemaes, 1948
  - Wegenfeld, Henri de, 1938
  - Weibel, Gustav, 1935
  - Weill, Irma, 1927
  - Welch, Robert H. W., Jr., 1952
  - Welles, Sumner [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Chaco War, Correspondence, Diplomatic]
    - 1933-1935
    - 1936-1938
  - Wells, Louise, 1919 (Box 65)
  - Wendling, Charles, 1952
  - Western Union Telegraph Company, undated
  - Weygand, Maxime, Gen., 1949
  - Wheeler, Howard, 1920
  - Whelan, Harriette Millar, 1927
  - Whelan, Thomas E., 1953
  - White, 1926
  - White, Francis, 1926-1934
  - White, Henry, 1919-1926
  - White, James C., 1920-1936
  - White, John Beaver, 1919-1934
  - White, John Campbell [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson]
    - 1920
    - 1921-1936
  - Whitehead, Lieutenant, 1930s
  - Whitehead, R. F., Rear Adm., 1954
  - Whitehouse, Sheldon [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson], 1925-1934
  - Whiteley, James Gustavus, 1920-1933
  - Whiting, Flora (Mrs. Giles), 1954
  - Whitlock, Brand and Ella, 1915-1921
  - Whitridge, Arnold, 1919
  - Whitridge, Arnold, Mrs., 1928
  - Wickersham, George W., 1920
  - Wielopolska, Sophie, 1921
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1920-1921
  - Wilcox, 1930s
  - Wilder & Buell, N.Y., 1920
  - Wile, Frederic William, 1932
  - Wiley, John C., 1952
  - Wiley, Luis, 1929
  - Wiley, Samuel Hamilton, 1926
  - Wilford, Ph., 1932
  - Wilkie, D. P. D., 1928
  - Wilkinson, James R., 1926
  - Willems, F., 1927
  - Willems, Jean (Fondation Francqui, Brussels), 1932
  - Willert, Arthur, 1920
  - Williams, H., 1918
  - Williams, J. D., 1930
  - Williams, James, Jr., 1927
  - Williams, Wythe, 1929-1934
  - Williamson, Charly, 1931
  - Williamson, Harold L., 1921-1932
  - Williamson, Margaret W., undated
  - Willis, Frances E., 1953-1954
  - Wills, Davis B., 1920-1921
  - Wills, Frances, 1935-1936
  - Wills, William Le Moyne and Susan G., 1927-1935
  - Willys, John N., 1931
  - Wilson, Charles S. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson], 1921-1926
  - Wilson, Edwin Carleton, 1932-1936
  - Wilson, F. M. Huntington, 1921-1925
  - Wilson, Florence, 1927
  - Wilson, Hugh R. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson] (Box 66)
    - 1918
    - 1919-1921
    - 1923-1924
    - 1925
    - 1926
    - 1927
    - 1928
    - 1929
    - 1930
    - 1931
    - 1932
    - 1933-1942
  - Wilson, Katherine (Mrs. Hugh R.), undated
  - Wilson, Thomas M., 1935 (Box 67)
  - Wilson, Warden McK. [See also: DIPLOMATIC POSTS, Belgium, Correspondence with Embassy], 1931
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1920
  - Winkler, Fred H., 1953
  - Winship, North, 1926
  - Winslow, Alan F. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson], 1919-1932
  - Winslow, Lawrence Lanier, 1919-1929
  - Winslow, Rollin R., 1927
  - Wiseman, William, 1942-1953
  - Wittouck, Albertine (Mrs. Franz), 1928-1954
  - Wittouck, Jean, 1924-1954
  - Wockerle, Anna(?), 1932
  - Wolfe, Robert, 1953
  - Women's Auxiliary to the Strangers' Hospital, Rio de Janeiro, 1936
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Washington, D.C., 1929-1930
  - Wood, Leona P. (Mrs. F. W.), 1928-1936
  - Wood, Otis F., 1927
  - Wood, W. A., Jr., Maj. Gen., 1953
  - Wood, Walter, 1921-1925
  - Woods, Arthur, 1922
  - Woodward, Stanley [See also: Clynans, H. and DIPLOMATIC POSTS, Belgium, Correspondence with Embassy], 1933-1934
  - Woodworth, E. S., 1936
  - Woolf, S. J., 1931
  - Woolley, Mary E., 1932-1933
  - Woolsey, Lester H., 1921-1936
  - Woolwine, J. E., 1920
  - Woracziczky, Count, 1928
  - Worksop, Winnie, 1942
  - Worsthorne, Alexander K., 1924-1953
  - Wouters d'Oplinter, 1932
  - Wright, Hamilton, 1925
  - Wright, I. A., 1918-1932
  - Wright, J. Butler [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson], 1920-1936
  - Xanthaky, George, 1952
  - Xanthaky, Theodore, 1933-1953
  - Yale University, New Haven, 1931
  - Yoch, Josephine, 1919
  - Young, C. C., 1920
  - Young, Evan, 1920-1931
  - Young, Harry R., 1924
  - Young, Kenneth, 1953
  - Young, Pamela Schnyler, undated
  - Young, Robert F., undated
  - Young, Samuel S., 1934-1936
  - Young, Wallace J., 1919
  - Ypersele, 1926
  - Yrureta-Goyena y Errazu, Joaquin de, 1932-1936
  - Yrureta-Goyena y Errazu, Manuel, 1926-1927
  - Zagorski, Steven D., 1921-1933
  - Zamoyski, Adam, 1928-1929
  - Zamoyski, Maurice, 1919-1924
  - Zapala, Father, 1920
  - Zeckendorf, William, 1954
  - Zeeland, Paul van, 1953
  - Zeldin, Mary-Barbara, 1954
  - Zoltowska, Sophy, 1923
  - Zoltowski, A., Count, 1920-1923
  - Zucker, A., 1921
  - Zurich de Reynold, Countess de, 1929
  - Zurpelle, R. M. J. van, 1928
  - Zyberk, Margaret Plater, Countess, 1921
- DIARIES, 1904-1947 (Reel 1, Boxes 68-72)
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1904-1905 (Box 68)
  - 1918
    - February-April
    - May
    - June
    - July
    - August
    - September-October
    - November (Box 69)
    - December
    - Microfilm copy of diary, 1918 March 14–November 30 (Reel 1)
  - 1919
    - January
    - February
    - March
    - March 28-April
    - May
    - June (Box 70)
    - July
    - August
    - September
    - October
    - November
    - December
  - "Paris to London via a number of places, June and July 1940,", June 9 -July 4
  - Herbert Hoover Food Mission, 1946-1947
    - 2 binders, 1946 March 17-June 19
    - 1946 March 17-May 12 (Box 71)
      - Four typewritten carboncopies
      - One typewritten photocopy
    - 1946 May 25-June 19
      - Three typewritten carboncopies
      - One typewritten photocopy
    - 2 folders, 1947 February 2-22 (Box 72)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1900-1952 (Boxes 72-78)
  Addresses, articles, drafts of books, essays, notes, outlines, and radio broadcasts, arranged alphabetically by title.
  See also: SUBJECT FILE/Belgium, King Leopold III - Controversy leading to his abdication, July 16, 1951/Writings by Gibson, and Provisional Intergovernmental Committee for the Movement of Migrants from Europe/Speeches by Gibson; DIPLOMATIC POSTS/Belgium and Brazil/Speeches; and DISARMAMENT CONFERENCES/Speeches.
  - Unidentified (Box 72)
  - Addresses
    - American Society of International Law, Washington, D.C., one printed copy, 1943 May 1
    - British War Relief Society, four typewritten carbon copies, 1942 December 1
    - Canterbury School Graduation Day, one typewritten carbon copy, 1943 June 5
    - Cleveland Community Chest Organization, one typewritten carbon copy, 1920 November 15
    - Testimonial dinner honoring Otto A. Rosalsky, Hotel Commodore, New York, one printed copy and one mimeograph copy, 1920 June 17
    - Yale Alumni Luncheon, New Haven, one typescript and two typewritten carbon copies, 1931 June 17
  - "An Approach to Peace Making," two typescripts and two carbon copies of a draft of remarks about a book on peace making, circa 1945
  - "Ask Questions," one typewritten carbon copy of a memorandum for an article, 1951 July 30
  - Belgium, The Country and Its People, one typescript and one typewritten carbon copy of an interview of Gibson regarding his book, 1939
  - "The Chronicles of Woolworth Abbey," one typescript (in a binder) and one typewritten carbon copy of a collection of short stories, 1940-1941
  - The Commission for Relief in Belgium during World War I, typewritten carbon and mimeograph copies of six memoranda and speeches
  - The Commission for Relief in Belgium during World War II, one typewritten carbon copy of a memorandum of conversations
  - Diplomacy," one typescript of a draft for a book and typewritten notes, 2.0 folders (Box 73)
  - "The Duty to Oppose," two printed copies of an article published in The Freeman, 1951 October 22
  - "The Feast of the Dead," one typescript of an account of Chinese customs in Los Angeles, circa 1900
  - "Feed the Starving Now," one copy of an article reprinted from Collier's Weekly, (with Herbert Hoover), 1943 February 20
  - "Food Is a Weapon," two printed copies of an article published in The Saturday Evening Post, and one reprint, 1942 February 21
  - The Foreign Service and the State Department, typescripts of memoranda and essays, 1940s and 1950s
  - "Foreigners Don't Like Santa Claus," one typewritten carbon copy of an article, 1951
  - Forewords
    - Homage to Paderewski, one photocopy of the printed form, circa 1939-1941
    - "Our National Policies in This Crisis," publication of Herbert Hoover's radio address, New York, one typewritten carbon copy, 1950 December 20
  - "Further New Approaches to Lasting Peace," two copies of an article reprinted from Collier's Weekly, (with Herbert Hoover), 1943 May-June
  - "German Rule in Belgium," typescript, mimeograph and carbon copies of an address delivered on several occasions, 1917-1918
  - "Here is the New Frontier," one typescript and two carbon copies of a draft of an article for This Week's Magazine, 1953 April 28
  - "History's Greatest Murder Trial," one printed copy of an article published in This Week's Magazine, (with Herbert Hoover), 1943 August 29
  - Humorous writings
    - Letters
      - General
      - On the foreign service
    - Light verse, limmericks
    - Short stories, 2.0 folders
    - Speeches
  - Introductions of various speakers, 1927-1929 (Box 74)
  - "Is Bi-Partisan Foreign Policy Desirable?," one typescript of an article, undated
  - A Journal from our Legation in Belgium, related correspondence and reviews of Gibson's book, 1917
  - "Justice for the Fremonts," one printed copy of an article published in the Ostrich Farm, South Pasadena, 1903
  - Letters to the editor
    - Indianopolis Star, one copy reprinted in the Christian Science Sentinel, 1945 June 16
    - The New York Times, three typewritten carbon copies, 1943 April 20
  - "The Little Dog Laughed," collection of handwritten and typewritten humorous short stories, light verse and puns, 2.0 folders
  - "Luxembourg," one typescript of an essay on the history of Luxemburg
  - Message to Belgian friends sent through OWI, one typewritten carbon copy, 1944 September 1
  - "My Battle with Moby Dick," one typewritten carbon copy of a draft of an article to be approved by Herbert Hoover, with possible comment or footnote by him, 1952 March 13
  - "A New Way to Make Peace," one printed copy of an article published in This Week's Magazine, 1943 November 7 (Box 75)
  - Notes
    - Diplomacy, the foreign service, international relations (handwritten and typewritten)
    - National interest in the post World War II era (handwritten)
    - Portraits of personalities and friends (handwritten and typewritten)
    - Relations with Europe in the post World War II era (handwritten)
  - "Peace or Revenge," typescripts of memoranda on the treatment of Germany after World War II
  - The Problems of Lasting Peace, galley proofs and related correspondence, interviews and reviews of Gibson's book, 1942
  - "The Prospects for Democracy in Europe," two typewritten carbon copies of a speech, 1939
  - Radio broadcasts, typescripts and carbon copies
    - On Brazil-U.S. friendship, 1936 July 4
    - On Spain, 1939 September 10
    - "The New Diplomacy,", 1939 November 4
    - "German Aims,", 1939 November 21
    - "Propaganda,", 1939 November 28
    - "The War for the Neutrals,", 1939 December 7
    - "Removing Russia from the League of Nations,", 1939 December 12
    - "Alice in Wonderland!,", 1939 December 23
    - "Slogans,", 1939 December 30
  - Radio forums, typewritten carbon and mimeograph copies
    - Unidentified
    - "Beyond Victory!,", circa 1941-1945
    - "Wake Up America!,", 1942 July 12
  - Recollection of a visit to Vienna and calling on President Koerner, one typescript and one typewritten carbon copy, 1952
  - Remarks, American Colony Dinner, Geneva, one typewritten mimeograph copy and one carbon copy, 1932 February 22
  - The Road to Foreign Policy, correspondence and reviews of Gibson's book, 1944 (Box 76)
  - "Secret Diplomacy," one typewritten carbon copy of a rough draft of an article, 1940
  - Speeches, typescripts and typewritten carbon copies
    - American Women's Voluntary Services, 1942 May 27
    - City Club of Milwaukee (with Joseph C. Grew), 1918 February 6
    - Dutch Treat Club, New York, 1939 April 15
    - Fourth of July Celebration, Hotel Beau Rivage, Geneva
      - 1925
      - 1926
    - Hoover Overseas and War Service Organizations Reunion Dinner, New York, 1929 March 3
    - On American foreign policy, 1920s
    - On Brazil, 1940 December 13
    - On Chaco War, 1935
    - On diplomacy, after, 1938
    - On Poland, 1920s
    - On the United States and World War I
    - On World War II
  - "Suggestions for the Republican Party," one typescript of a memorandum, 1947 January
  - "What Diplomacy Is and Isn't," one typewritten carbon copy of an essay
  - "What Price Peace?," one printed copy of an article published in This Week's Magazine, 1944 October 8
  - "Widow Grogan's Reflections" and other short stories and articles, typescripts and typewritten carbon copies
  - "A World of Free Peoples," one typescript of a speech before the Rotary Club, circa 1942-1944
  - "The World We Want," one typewritten copy, circa 1942-1945
  - Five binders put together by Hugh Gibson, containing typewritten copies of addresses, broadcasts and remarks, index in box 77, 1927-1947 (Boxes 77-78)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1902-1955 (Boxes 79-97)
  Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and studies, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - American Child Health Association, N.Y., 1923 (Box 79)
  - American Club(?), London, 1940
  - The American Committee to Aid the University of Nymegen (Holland), N.Y., (Hugh Gibson, chairman), 1947-1953
  - American Consular Bulletin, Washington, D.C., Volume IV, No. 1, 1922 January
  - American Mission of Relief for Poland, 1919
  - American Red Cross, 1918-1945
  - American Relief Administration, N.Y.
    - General, 1919-1923
    - Austria, 1922-1923
    - Soviet Union [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Castle, William, October 8, 1921]
  - Armenia, 1920
  - Beard, Charles A. and Mary R.
  - Belgium
    - General
    - Inter-war period [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Castle, William, January 20, 1931]
    - King Leopold III - Controversy leading to his abdication, 1951 July 16
      - Clippings, correspondence
      - Official documents from World War II used as evidence, including letters by Hitler, Adm. Keyes, Lord Gort, etc.
      - Writings by Gibson
    - Post-World War II period
    - World War I (Box 80)
      - General [See also: Lancken, Baron von der and CORRESPONDENCE, Ridder, A.]
      - German rule and atrocities
      - Relief [See also: Hoover, Herbert, Relief work, World War I - Belgium]
    - World War II
      - General
      - Relief [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Aldrich]
      - Surrender of the Belgian Army, May 28, 1940
  - Bliss, Robert W.
  - Bolivia, 1954
  - Boyce, Richard F., "The American Consul in Action and What It Means to Be One"
  - Brazil, 1936
  - Briand, Aristide - Plan for a Proposed Federation of Europe, 1930
  - Briand-Kellogg Pact, 1928
  - Briggs, Ellis O.
  - Browne, Albert S. (secretary of Gibson) - Accounts during London Naval Conference, 1930
  - Buell, Raymond L., "Sea Law under the Kellogg Pact,", May 15, 1929
  - Bullitt, William [See: CORRESPONDENCE, Shepardson, Whitney]
  - C.R.B. Bulletin, May 1, 1920
  - C.R.B. Educational Foundation, Inc., N.Y.
  - California - Movement towards autonomy, 1919
  - Carpenter, Ford A., "Weather and Its Effects on Air Transport,", 1929
  - Carr, Wilbur J. [See also: American Consular Bulletin]
  - Castle, William R., Jr., "Diplomacy under the New Deal,", 1936
  - Cavell, Edith
  - Central Europe, 1935
  - Chaco War between Bolivia and Paraguay, and Peace Conference in Buenos Aires [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Dawson, Allan, August 24 and 30, 1935], 1935-1936
    - Correspondence
      - Diplomatic
        - 1935 January - 1936 March
        - 1936 April-October (Box 81)
      - Personal, 1935 May 8-November 11
    - Despatches of American Delegation to Peace Conference
      - 1935 November 25 (no. 93) - 1936 April 16 (no. 160)
      - 1936 April 17 (no. 162) - July 7 (no. 210) (Box 82)
      - 1936 July 14 (no. 211) - September 24 (no. 280)
      - 1936 September 28 (no. 281) - 1937 January 5 (no. 348) (Box 83)
      - 1937 January 7 (no. 349) - January 14 (no. 353)
    - Personal expenses, 1935-1936
  - Chamberlain, Austen, Sir
  - Chile - Political situation, 1924
  - Colby, Bainbridge - Address delivered before the Democratic National Convention, San Francisco, July 2, 1920
  - Colcord, Samuel, "A Way to Insure the Permanence of the Multilateral Treaty to Outlaw War"
  - Collective security
  - College Jean de Brebeuf, Montreal
  - Committee on Public Information, Washington, D.C., 1918
  - Communist International - VI Congress, August 28, 1929
  - Conference of Experts for a Moratorium on Intergovernmental Debts, London [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Gilchrist, Stockton, July 11 and Tuck, William Hallam, July 7 and DIPLOMATIC POSTS, Belgium, Correspondence with Embassy, Ferdinand L. Mayer], 1931
    - Committees
      - Of Experts
        - General
        - Directory
        - Documents
        - Memoranda (Box 84)
          - General
          - Of conversations
        - Miscellaneous
        - Report
        - Sub-Committees
          - On Deliveries in Kind
          - On Non-German Questions
      - Of Finance Ministers
    - Conference held in the Prime Minister's Room - Stenographic notes of 1st, 2nd, 3rd and 4th meetings
    - Directory
    - Documents
      - General
      - Bulgaria [See also: Greece]
      - Greece [See also: Bulgaria]
      - Hungary
      - Romania
      - Yugoslavia
    - Final declaration (Box 85)
    - German-Belgian negotiations
    - Herbert Hoover's proposal of, June 21
      - Text
      - Reactions and statements from various countries
    - Miscellaneous
    - Press clippings
    - Reports and letters on situation in Europe (not by Gibson)
    - Telegrams, in and outgoing, between the Secretary of State and various American embassies and consulates
      - Basel
      - Belgrade
      - Berlin
      - Brussels
      - Budapest
      - London
      - Paris
        - Received in Paris
        - Sent from Paris
      - Rome
      - Sofia
      - Vienna
    - U.S. Mixed Claims Commission
  - Coolidge, Calvin - Speech before the American Legion, Washington, D.C., November 11, 1928
  - Craigie, Robert Leslie
  - Czechoslovakia, 1918-1924
  - Davies, David, "The Problem of Disarmament" (Box 86)
  - Diplomacy
  - Diplomatic immunities
  - Durand, E. D., "The Alleged Imperialism of Poland,", 1920
  - Eastern Galicia, 1919
  - Economic history
  - The Educational Reviewer, New York, 1950-1951
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1949-1954
  - Elisabeth, Queen of Belgium, 1928
  - L'est polonais, Warsaw, October 20, 1920
  - Europe, ca. 1919-1923
  - European Children's Fund
    - Attacks upon
    - In Austria, 1920-1921
    - Mission to Poland, 1919-1922
  - European Relief - World War II [See also: Hoover, Herbert, Relief Work, World War II - The Hoover Plan]
    - General, 2.0 folders
    - Appeals from various individuals and organizations to send food
    - Correspondence
      - (l), 1940
      - (2), 1940 (Box 87)
      - 1941
        - January-February
          - A-O
          - P-Z
        - March (Box 88)
          - A-O
          - P-Z
        - April
        - May
          - A-O
          - P-Z
      - 1941-1942 (Box 89)
    - Food maps
    - Printed matter
    - Telegrams
      - (1), 1940
      - (2), 1940
      - (3), 1940
      - 1941
        - Received
        - Sent (Box 90)
  - European Relief Council, 1920
  - Eyck, Andrew Ten [See: CORRESPONDENCE, Baldwin, Elbert F.]
  - Ferguson, Homer, "Remarks for Delivery in the Senate,", 1951 January 16
  - Fishing
  - Flynn, John T., The Thought Police: An Episode in Radical Bigotry, N.Y., 1946
  - Ford, Henry [See: Jewish Question, General]
  - France - Foreign relations
    - Germany, 1932
    - Poland, 1918(?)-1932
  - Fremont, Jessie Benton, Mrs.
  - Fremont, John C., Gen.
  - Fuerstenberg, Elisabeth von, Countess
  - Germany
    - General, 1921-1932
    - Naval Question, 1912-1914
    - World War I. Speech of Chancellor Theobald von Bethmann Hollweg before the Reichstag session of, December 2, 1914
  - Gibson, Mary (Mrs. Frank A.)
  - Gibson, Michael
  - Gibson, Ynes
    - General [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Cobian, Eduardo]
    - Correspondence
      - Clary, Resy
      - Clary, Sophie
      - Potocka, Betka
      - Villalobar, Marquis de
      - Others
    - Driver's license, 1925
  - Gibson Code (for the transmission and translation of languages
  - Goedeke, Walter John (Box 91)
  - Great Britain - Schools, 1930
  - Griffiths, Austin E., George Washington, World Court, League of Nations, 1923
  - Halpert, Thaddeus
  - Hard, William, "Tour of Central Europe,", 1921
  - Harding, Warren G.
  - Harmon, Clifford
  - Hawkins, Harry C.
  - Herbert, Felix, Senator
  - Holland, Kenneth [See: CORRESPONDENCE, Bent, Ernest F.]
  - Honduras
  - Honeij, James A., "How Long Will Poland Last?", 1921
  - Hoover, Herbert C. [See also: American Child Health Association and CORRESPONDENCE, King, Alice]
    - General
    - Correspondence [See also: MacDonald, J. Ramsay]
    - Relief work
      - World War I - Belgium
      - World War II - The Hoover Plan
    - Speeches
  - Howland, Samuel Shaw
  - Humor
  - Hurley, Edward N., "World Industrial Leaders Can Prevent War,", 1929
  - Interallied Committee for the Re-Education of War Cripples, 1918
  - Interallied Mission to Countries of Former Austro-Hungarian Empire, 1919 January
  - Interallied Mission to Poland [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Dresel, Ellis Loring, October 5, 1920]
    - General
    - Of Control for Teschen
    - Sub-Committee for Posen
  - International Catholic Migration Commission, Geneva, 1954-1955
  - International Conciliation, N.Y., 1924 February
  - Interparliamentary Union Conference, Bern and Geneva, 1924
  - Italy
  - Jefferson, Thomas (Box 92)
  - Jewish question
    - General
    - Poland
      - General
      - Mission to Poland (Henry Morgenthau)
      - Reports by Gibson [See also: DIPLOMATIC POSTS, Poland, Reports, Weekly Political Reports]
    - United States
  - Kellogg, Vernon, "Washington Five and Eight O' Clocks,", 1920
  - Kennan, George F.
  - Kitchener, Horatio Herbert, Lord
  - Klopstock, Paul, "Poland Today?" (?), 1920
  - Knights of Columbus
  - Lancken, Baron von der
  - Lansing, Robert
  - Latin America, 1954
  - Lausanne Conference with regard to the convening of a world economic and financial conference, 1932
  - League of Nations, Geneva
    - General